### **RACHEL GUNDY**

2123 4TH AVE N. 98109 SEATTLE WA · (509)552-1405 · RACHELM.GUNDY@GMAIL.COM

# SUMMARY:

Highly capable, results-driven and self-motivated product manager with over 10 years of record achievement and demonstrated success in technical project, product and operations management. Deep proponent of driving collaboration through consensus decision making and leading by example. Possesses strong analytical and management/leadership skills. Driven by working on products that delight users, solves complex customer problems with simple solutions, while driving significant business outcomes. Highly experienced in agile methodology, software and web development, along with proven success of implementing scrum process.

### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Cleaning, manipulating, and analyzing large sets of data for trending, benchmarking, statistical analysis and financial forecasting.
- Creation of visual dashboards utilizing Excel, Power BI, SQL and R.
- Developing test plans, allocating and converting results into presentation format for A/B testing.
- Automating processes with VBAs.

- Adept in SAP, Google Analytics, Access, SQL, R, Excel, GitHub, Oracle, Power BI, Jira and Confluence.
- Four years of experience in managing an average size team of 10 through collaboration, consensus decision making and leading by example.
- Creating designs that are scalable and sustainable.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### MarketLeader

**Product Manager, Analytics -** December 2017 – Present

Support senior leadership on initiatives to increase revenue, reduce expenses and mitigate risks by developing cost-benefit analysis, financial models to quantify outcomes and reviewing comparative operating results.

- Cut reporting footprint in half by automating reporting into updated SQL queries interfacing into Power BI, resulting in increased efficiency by identifying redundancies in reporting and a monthly savings of 10%.
- Prepare detailed financial modeling for new and existing assets for the M&A team, including variance analysis, debt analysis, cash flow projections and return analysis.
- Aggregate data from multiple sources to compile into digestible dashboards on product types and consumer habits; this resulted in improved customer lifetime value by 8%.

### SmartAction

Sr. Project Manager - June 2016 - November 2017

End-to-end product ownership to successfully deliver customized machine-learning based application for clients. Post-launch implementation and present application development opportunities through data analysis utilizing Excel, SQL and ETL.

- Managed full project cycle, from implementation strategy including API mapping, task and resource prioritization, to user adoption analytics, ensuring 15 successful application launches.
- Supported external partners in development and improvement of API, including updating ETL applications onto API platform to reduce render times and streamline data service by 10%.
- Provided technical assistance and support to external partners.
- Used data and metrics, with tool such as excel, to develop quarterly business reports for clients and internal teams resulting in discussion and implementation on opportunities for growth into new programs.
- Improved customer engagement in application by focusing on:
  - o Quantifying behavior trends of customer demographic.
  - Evaluating effectiveness of components used in application to improve success.
  - Measuring repeat users per time period to improve customer experience.
  - Determine need for A/B testing in application.
- Reduced turnaround time for project life cycle by implementing:

- Created automated user form in VBA to standardized testing scenarios and testing results submissions.
- Kanban boards and Epics to prioritize project backlog.
- Improved escalation process through implementation of RACI chart.
- Served as key liaison on cross-functional teams to engineering, marketing and sales guaranteeing consistent product development and messaging.

### Nike

### Nike+ Procurement Analyst - June 2015- May 2016

Lead the Nike+ procurement operations yearly budget cycle; included conceptualization, execution and monitoring while managing risks, timelines and resources for revenue recognition. Responsible for improving work efficiency, performance, department profitability and KPI by instilling effective methods, strategies and expense/allowance control. Main objective to deliver the mobile application and technology within budget.

- Developed and maintained detailed process plans including work flow charts, resulting in smaller deviations from projected interdepartmental budgets.
- Generated error reports to analyze issues to find root cause. Presented issues to affected departments and worked on mitigation plan, develop solution, test, and deploy fix.
- Supervised operation deliverables in line with the business scope.
  - o Standardized projection for billable hours for external partners
  - o Improved visibility of client history through integration of Salesforce
- Monitored and improved key performance indices.
  - o Achieved a less than 5% deviation from budget
  - o Accomplished goal of 10% increase in new strategic partnerships
  - o Met go live production deadlines
- Provided status reports to company sponsors.
- Acted as a liaison with other divisions; interacted with managers for different areas to harmoniously integrate better communication channels and mutually benefit with current strategies.

# **Home Builders Foundation**

# **Product Consultant -** August 2014- May 2015

Consulted clients on proposed donor strategies and new media tools and website.

- Spearheaded marketing research in HBF shelters and partnered with teammates, donors, and stakeholders to generate an interactive website and social media package that increased brand awareness and new donor support.
- Collected, data mined and analyzed data on the Portland homeless population, resulting in creation of an analytical dashboard that generates statistics and dollar-value impacts to generate reports to communicate the organization's impact.

# Peace Corps - Rwanda

# Health Service Analyst Volunteer - May 2012- January 2014

Consulted hospital on engagement strategies, developed KPIs and sustainable analytics to monitor success of engagement.

- Analyzed customer base demographics, client retention trends, and profitability of service and products to identify key needs of community and Health Center.
- Identified breakdowns in organizational processes through managing inter-division focus groups, then recommended and implemented changes.
- Analyzed data, identified community health issues and created three new Health Center Programs which increased rates of access to use by 30%, which improved client relationships.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Willamette University,** Salem, OR August 2014 - May 2016 MBA in Operations and Finance

**University of Hawaii at Manoa,** Honolulu, HI January 2008 - June 2011 Bachelor of Arts